在座的各位大家好，感谢到场
正如 Simon 介绍的，我是 Lea
这就是 border-radius 先生（戏称）
他看起来简单得就像是一个
出自小儿书里面的符号一样
因为许多，甚至每一位程序员
都不认为 border-radius 很酷
然而，今天我要这里证明，你们错了
border-radius 不仅现在很酷
并且在将来
《Background and Borders Level 4》发表 以后
他也会变得难以置信的酷
前提是这些技术能在浏览器中实现
所以大多数人
认为 border-radius 不酷
是因为他们只看到了冰山一角
这看起来就像你设置了一个值
然后得到了一些圆角
你设置的值越大
得到的圆角越大
这个值只是设置了
每个角上圆弧的半径
很多人都知道我们可以
为每一个角设置不同的值
例如通过设置 2 个值或者 3 个值
甚至 4 个值
他们沿着顺时针方向，从左上角开始
然而这些都很简单对吧
现在有个例子
它看起来就像一个普通的border-radius，
我们有 900 个像素
左上角的半径长度为 900 像素
其他的角半径长度都是 90 像素
这意味着，为了遵循这个设置
我们总共需要 990 像素
但是水平方向上我们只有 540 像素
420 vertically so where's all these
垂直方向只有 420 像素，所以
这些半径要如何适应呢
所以浏览器通常不得不做一些调整，
因为他们显然不能遵循这个设定，
所以当 border-radius 不合适时
浏览器做这种调整
是为了尝试维持不同半径之间的比率。
所以在这种情况下
即使左上角的半径不是 900
它实际上是 308 和 81
仍然是右上角的 10 倍大小
右上角是 38 像素
在规范中有这么一段话，
当相邻的两个 border-radius 之和
超出了 border box 的尺寸，
用户代理（浏览器）必须适当减少所有的 border-radius 的值
用户代理（浏览器）必须适当减少所有的 border-radius 的值，
直到他们不再出现重叠，这段话的意思是
如果 border-radius 不合适
你只需要适当缩小他们，
这就是为什么我们可以声明一个很大的值来制作圆环，
并且不论这个值有多大。
例如，不论这个值 是 900 还是别的任何值
it still stays a circle because it's
它永远保持圆形，
scaled down and here's a cool demo which
因为它被缩小了，这里有一个很酷的 demo
shows the number of different radii we
展示了不同数值的半径
can make of different shapes we can make
我们可以设置成不同的形状
just with what I've shown so far however
就像我演示的一样，
the the border radius rabbit hole goes
然而 border-radius 半径的坑比这还要深，
deeper than that so here we wanted to
make an ellipse but an ellipse is not
我们想要制作一个椭圆 ，
possible to make through parts of a
但是一个椭圆不可能用我刚刚演示的这些圆环的部分来构成的
circle which is what I've showed so I've
shown so far however if we use a slash
然而，如果我们用一个斜杠
we can specify different horizontal and
我们就可以指定不同的水平和垂直的半径
vertical radii so effectively we can
所以我们可以
make shapes out of parts of ellipses
高效地制做出椭圆的组成部分
instead of parts of circles so if we
而不是圆环的组成部分，
make this value bigger you can see how
所以如果我们将这个值设置地更大，你就能看到
it works
它是如何工作的
and if it's exactly the same as half of
如果它刚好是我们宽度的一半，
our width and the vertical one is half
并且垂直的值是高度的一半，
of our quiet we have an ellipse so the
我们就可以得到一个椭圆，
next logical question is can we make
所以下面的逻辑问题是，我们能够制作半个椭圆吗？
half an ellipse so the problem with this
所以这个椭圆的问题就是
ellipse is that it's not very flexible
它不是很灵活
if we increase the width you can see
如果我们增加宽度，你就能看到
that it's not an ellipse anymore it's a
它不再是一个椭圆了
weird sort of cylindrical shape and of
这是一个很奇怪的圆柱形了
course we can change this to reflect the
当然，我们可以改变这个来改变新的宽度
new width and it's an ellipse again but
它又是一个椭圆了，
it's not very portable is it
但是这不是很方便不对吧
however border-radius also accepts
然而， border-radius 也可以接受百分数，
percentages and percentages are resolved
百分数的解析是基于对应的方向的
to pay based on the corresponding
dimension horizontally they're based on
水平方向是基于宽度
the width and vertically based on the
垂直方向是基于高度
height and since they're the same number
因为在斜线的前后是相同的数字，
before and after the slash we don't even
我们甚至可以不需要使用斜线了，
need the slash anymore so now I can just
现在我可以直接改变两个方向的值，
change the dimensions and it just
然后它就会自然地起作用了。
naturally works so half an ellipse would
自然地起作用了。所以一个半椭圆
be because it's symmetric because this
因为它是对称的，
half ellipse is symmetrical horizontally
因为这个半椭圆是水平对称的
it's just 50% and then we have a really
它就是是50%。然后我们在上面的拐角这里
large radii for the top corners in fact
有很大的半径，事实上是100%
100% and zero for the bottom ones and
底部的拐角半径是 0
there you have half of reef very
然后你就得到了半个鹅卵石一样
flexible ellipse so the next question is
非常柔软的椭圆。所以接下来的问题是
can we make a quarter ellipse a quarter
我们可以作出一个 1/4 的椭圆吗？
ellipse just has a hundred percent
一个 1/4 椭圆在拐角处
radius in the corner in the part where
有 100% 的半径，在这个部分，
in the corner it's rounded in this case
在这个例子中，
the top right corner so if we specify a
它在一个右上方的拐角出处变圆
hundred percent horizontally a hundred
所以如果我们指定一个水平的 100%
percent for the top right left corner
右上角也指定一个 100%
and zero for the other corners for both
在其他拐角处，同时设置水平和垂直半径为 0
horizontal and vertical radii radiuses
there we have a quarter ellipse it
这样，我们就有一个 1/4 椭圆了
doesn't matter what dimensions we have
不论我们改变什么方向
it's still it's still flexible and we
它都很灵活
don't even need both parts because
我们甚至不用同时使用这两部分
they're the same so we don't even need
因为他们是相等的，所以我们甚至不需要
the slash so the next question is can we
这个斜线。所以接下来的问题是
make a quarter ellipse now sorry we
我们可以制作一个 1/4 椭圆吗？抱歉，我们不能
can't not with border-radius at least
最终不是用 border-radius 实现的
you can still use SVG
但你还是可以用 SVG （来实现）
but here are a few more shapes you can
还有一些其他形状，
make with water radius and these are
你可以用 border-radius 做出来，
just a few examples I came up with last
这只是昨天晚上我想出来的一小部分
night there are many many more you can
还有很多其他的你可以用 border-radius 实现。
use water radius for this demo is a
little old but I like it because it
这些 demo 有点旧了，但是我喜欢它们，
shows how similar I used regular curves
因为它展示显示了我是如何用类似的方式，
and different border-radius uses to make
通过常规曲线和不同的 border-radius 设置来制作按钮
buttons actually look good and I've used
事实上看起来还不错，
to regular curves and border-radius to
而且我已经用过常规曲线和 border-radius
make the to make pebbles that look more
来制作一些鹅卵石，看起来非常自然
natural in all sorts of things and you
might be wondering why should we go
你可能好奇为什么我们要了解这些知识，而不直接用图片
through this and not just use images the
cool thing about border-radius is that
border-radius 的一件很酷的事情就是
it's also animatable so we can use
它是可以用来制作动画的，
transitions and animations on it so here
所以我们可以在它上面使用 transitions 和  animations ，
when when I hover over it it switches
所以当我悬停在它上面的时候，
from this radius which is if you
它就从这个半径变化了，
remember used to create half ellipse to
如果你还记得用过这个来创造一个半椭圆
50% and you can animate between any two
改成 50% ，然后你可以在任意两个半径之间创作动画
radii I can even convert this into an
我甚至可以将这个转换成一个动画，
animation and have it ran continuously
让它一直动
without even me having to hover over it
甚至不需要我在它上面悬停
and we can even add a bottom offset make
我们甚至可以添加一个底部的偏移，
it look like it's jumping which i think
来让他看起来是在跳动，
is kind of cool you can make all sorts
我认为这很酷，你可以用 border-radius
of different animations with
做出各种各样的动画效果
border-radius
and there's a lot of untapped potential
还有很多尚未开发的潜力
there because most people don't even
因为大多数人甚至不会
think to animate border-radius however
想到 border-radius 动画，
at some point you reach a point where
然而在一些情况下，你可能会遇到
you need to add content in your dev that
你需要在 div 中添加文字内容
you've been using all this all these
就可以使用所有这些（技巧）
cool boarder radii on it and as you can
很酷的 border-radius，
see the situation is not great text
如你所见，情况并不妙
wrapping doesn't follow border-radius in
在小半径的情况下
in smaller radii you can sort of use
文字并没有跟随 border-radius，
padding to help with that and the bigger
你可以用一点点 padding 来帮下忙，
the radio is the bigger the padding but
而且半径越大，padding 就要越大，
that also reduces the space you have for
但是这也减少了文字能使用的空间
the text so unfortunately right now
不幸的是，
there's no solution for this but in the
目前这个情况还没有解决办法，
future we will have something a property
但是在将来，我们将会有一些东西，
that's called shape inside
一个叫作 shape inside 的属性
and if we specify content box it just
如果我们指定了 content box，
naturally follows the content box
文字就会自然地遵循 content box 的拐角
rounding it's actually a little buggy in
这实际上是目前 Chrome 中的一个小小的 bug，
chrome right now because the Chrome has
因为 Chrome 有一个试验性的实现，
an experimental implementation but it's
a bit buggy as you can see because it
但这是一个小 bug，如你所见，
doesn't subtract padding from the
因为它没有像它应该的那样
rounding like it should this will be in
从拐角减去 padding，
CSS shapes level - it wasn't level one
这将出现在 CSS Shape Level 2 中，而不是 Level 1
but it got deferred unfortunately and it
但是不幸的是它被延期了（当前是2014年）
will be really cool because there's no
那将会是真正的酷 ，
other solution to this right now
因为目前还找不到其他的解决方案
at some point you might need to use
有一些情况下你可能需要用到
JavaScript to read back values of world
JavaScript 来读取 border-radius 的值
radius and you would expect since border
你可能会期待，因为 border-radius
radius is rather old property you would
是一个很老的属性了，
expect browsers to be relatively
你可能希望浏览器能相对地
compatible with each other right I'm
彼此适应对吧？ 抱歉
sorry that's not quite the case so soon
情况并非如此
we are running some simple JavaScript to
我们立刻就能运行一些简单的 JavaScript 来
get a reference to the element and then
得到元素的引用 ，
read back the computed style in this
然后读取计算的样式值，在这个例子中
case for border top left is so if you
就是 “borderTopLeftRadius”，
look at the code here border top left is
如果你看看这里的代码，左上边是 100%
a hundred percent which will get
这将会被解析成 540 的水平像素
resolved to 540 pixels horizontally and
这将会被解析成 540 的水平像素和 420 的垂直像素，
420 pixels however because horizontally
因为水平方向上
we have to fit in a hundred 100 percent
我们必须适应 100% 加上 2 em，
plus two M's and vertically we have to
垂直方向上我们必须
fit in 100% plus 40 pixels sorry plus 50
适应 100% 加上 40 像素，抱歉，加上 50%
percent the hundred percent needs to be
100% 需要被缩小
scaled down
so the actual used values will not be
所以实际上使用的值将不是水平 540 像素，
540 pixels horizontally or 420
也不是垂直 420 像素
vertically there will be smaller so what
将会更小，所以浏览器将会反馈什么？
will browsers report back will they
report back a hundred percent that we
它会反馈一个我们指定的 100% 吗？
specified will they report back the
会反馈一个我们指定的未经缩小的宽度和高度的值吗？
width and height values without scaling
them down or will they report back the
或者会反馈这个实际上使用的值吗？
actual used values so what they do is
浏览器做的是
that they actually disagree in that so
各种浏览器实际在这一点上不一致
most browsers will return a hundred
大多数浏览器将会返回一个 100%
percent which is the value we specified
这是我们指定的
Firefox will return the actual used
Firefox 将会返回实际使用的值
values which is very useful but
这是非常有用的，
different from what any of the other
但是和其他浏览器的行为都不一样
browsers do I'm hoping that the other
我希望其他的浏览器
browsers will change to do what Firefox
将来能够变成 Firefox 这样
does but it will probably be the other
但是也可能是另一种方式
way around
and this is why I'm using Firefox for
这就是为什么我用 Firefox 来讲这个主题
this talk actually because the values
实际上是因为它返回的值
that returns are much more useful
要有用的多
similarly if we try to read back the top
类似的，如果我们尝试读取右上角的半径
right radius this one which is two amps
这个 2em 的值
what will the browser's return to us two
浏览器会返回什么给我们
M's converted to pixels two M's
2em 转换成像素？
converted to pixels and scaled down so
2em转换成像素，然后缩小？
most browsers will just convert the MS
所以大多数浏览器会只将 2em 转换成像素
to pixels and return that Firefox will
然后将值返回，Firefox 将会返回实际使用的值，
return the actual used value which is
它会更小
smaller because it needs to be scaled
因为它需要被缩小
down so things are not great in that
所以在这方面，并不是很好
aspect so I've showed you a little of
所以今天我已经展示了一些
what you can do with water radius today
你可以用 border-radius 做的事情
but the future holds so many cool things
但是对 border-radius 来说，未来还有很多很酷的东西
for border-radius
because right now in the draft for
因为目前在
backgrounds and waters level 4 there's a
《Backgrounds And Border Level 4》的草案中
property called border cordon shape and
有一个属性叫作 Border-Corner-Shape
obviously many things will change in it
很显然，其中许多事情都会改变
before it makes it into an actual spec
在它被写入实际的规范之前
and into an actual browser I'm hoping
然后进入到实际的浏览器中
the name will change because it's awful
我希望它的名字能改一下，因为这很糟糕
and we're open to suggestions about that
我们对此都很开放
by the way
顺便一提
so border corner shape allows you to
所以 Border-Corner-Shape 允许你
change what border radius does it still
改变 border-radius 的作用，它仍然遵循
follows the size specified by border
border-radius 指定的值
radius but the shape of the corners is
但是拐角的形状不同了
different the default shape is curved
默认的形状是弯曲的
which is what you can do with water
也就是现在 border-radius 默认的效果
radius today you can have bevel 4 cut
你可以使用  Level 4 剪下拐角
out corners and this doesn't just allow
不仅仅是允许你剪下拐角，
you to do cut out corners it allows you
to do all sorts of cool stuff for
它允许你做出各种各样的很酷的效果
example rhombi would just be a border
例如，菱形就是一个
radius 50% or hexagons with just this or
50% 的 border-radius，六边形就是这个
you can do triangles like this or you
或者你可以做一些三角形像这样，
can do trapezoids by specifying a fixed
或者你可以做一个体型，通过指定一个固定的
horizontal border radius instead of a
水平 border-radius 而不是一个的百分比，
percentage one based one and scoop is
凹槽也很酷
also pretty cool by default it makes
默认情况下，它创造了这样一种形状，
this sort of shape but it can also be
但是她也可以被利用
exploited to do all sorts of cool shapes
来做出各种各样的酷炫的形状
like the starlit looks like this not
比如像这样的星光
just not as useful it doesn't show now
不仅仅是有用，它没有显示出来
because I've specified 50% so not just
因为我已经指定了 50% ，所以不仅仅是有用
not as useful it does it cut out it cuts
它从每个拐角
out rectangles from each corner
剪下了矩形
but it can be used for things like our
但是它可以被用来做一些像是
no crosses for example so imagine the
“no crosses” 的东西，举个例子
possibilities if we get boarder corner
想象一下如果我们特意使用 border-corner-shape 的可能性，
shape especially since we'll actually be
因为我们实际上
able to use different corner shapes for
将会在每个拐角上
each corner however until then since
使用不同的拐角形状，直到那时
this is not in any browser yet you can
因为这还不能在任意浏览器中实现
sort of emulate this effect by using
你可以模仿这种效果，通过在这里
gradients here have used four gradients
使用 gradient，这里使用了 4 个 gradient
one for each quarter you can see how
每一个负责 1/4 ，你可以看到它是如何工作的
this works
if I change the color of this one to
例如如果我将这个的颜色
black for example so each of those
改为黑色，所以其中每一个 gradient
gradients covers a quarter and it's a
都覆盖了1/4，并且它是一个
linear gradient with an angle like this
线性的 gradient，具有一个这样的角
and that can change the size of the
我们可以改变这个效果的大小
effect by changing the position of the
通过改变 color stop（没明白什么意思） 中的位置
color stop I've used the second color
第二个 color stop 的位置是 0，
stop has a position of zero so that it
it it automatically adjusts the fifty
所以它自动的调整了 50 像素
pixels or whatever I specify here so I
或者任何我在这里设定的值
don't have to change two values and this
所以我不必改变两个值
will actually be this would be much more
如果你将它变成一个 SAS mixin
usable if you turn it into a SAS mixin
这将是，这可能会是更加有用的
because I know it has a little
repetition here
and you can use radial gradients in the
你也可以用同样的方式
same fashion if I change this for
使用径向 gradient，例如，如果我把这个
example to black you can see how it
改成黑色，你就可以看到它是如何工作的了
works or I can change this to green
或者我把它改成绿色，或者随便别的什么颜色
whatever and I can change the size and
我可以改变大小
they work the same way as the scope
他们和 border-corner-shape 的工作原理相同
border corner shape will I know it's not
我知道这还不完美
perfect but it's a way to do it right
但是这是目前不用任何外部图片或者别的东西的情况下
now without using any external images or
正确做这件事的方法
anything so that's actually about it
所以这就是这些内容了
thank you very much
非常感谢你们